<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Silas-Raye.github.io]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Silas-Raye.github.io</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 03:06:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 03:06:13 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[readme]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://s7ygian.itch.io/the-observer-2" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://s7ygian.itch.io/the-observer-2" target="_blank">Play The Observer</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://itch.io/jam/historically-accurate-game-jam-8/rate/2556269" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://itch.io/jam/historically-accurate-game-jam-8/rate/2556269" target="_blank">Game Jam Submission and Rating</a><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Silas-Raye/Elijah-Lovejoy-Game" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Silas-Raye/Elijah-Lovejoy-Game" target="_blank">Source Code</a><br>About The Game<br>
I created The Observer for my first ever <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_jam" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_jam" target="_blank">game jam</a>. The game jam was called <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://itch.io/jam/historically-accurate-game-jam-8" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://itch.io/jam/historically-accurate-game-jam-8" target="_blank">Historically Accurate Game Jam 8</a> or HAGJ8 for short, and the topic was famous assassinations. I chose to make a game about the abolitionist Elijah Parrish Lovejoy. A man who had his printing press destroyed four times! The structure of the game is based on actual historical events. You can read about them by clicking "History" on the game's homepage. Each level you must save enough money to buy a new printing press before before a mob ransacks your shop. Like Lovejoy you are encouraged to stop printing as continuing to play means risking your life and your livelihood for the sake of what you believe in.<br>Screenshots<br>
<img alt="Screenshot 1" src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1MzY4NTczLnBuZw==/original/P7uLtX.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><br><img alt="Screenshot 2" src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1MzY4NTc1LnBuZw==/original/eTqgp1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><br><img alt="Screenshot 3" src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1MzY4NTc4LnBuZw==/original/2XjCwM.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><br>Disclaimer<br>
The backgrounds where made by and AI (Midjourney) and then touched up and stitched together by me. I would have preferred to use all human made art for the game, but this was impossible considering the small team and time constraint. The three character sprites where made by Momonga, the sound was made by Kaavee, the idea for the game was mine, and Maddhaus helped with play testing and development.<br><br><br>Coding, Creation of Background Art Using AI, Game Concept, and Graphics<br><br>Ideation, Play Testing, and Design Consulting<br><br>Sound Design and Music<br><br>Pixel Art Character Sprites]]></description><link>readme.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">readme.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 22:21:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1MzY4NTczLnBuZw==/original/P7uLtX.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://img.itch.zone/aW1nLzE1MzY4NTczLnBuZw==/original/P7uLtX.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hey I'm Silas Raye,]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>I graduated from the University of Florida in December of 2023. I see myself as a strategic thinker, and someone who values the importance of data to extract insights and inform better decision making.<br>I've always had a fascination with numbers due to my dyslexia, which made Math a more welcoming subject than English. Embracing this affinity, I delved into the world of technology early on. My dyslexia led me to adopt emerging tools like voice-to-text and text-to-speech when they were still in their infancy. Because of this, I became enthralled with the progress in machine learning and have made an effort to stay on the forefront of artificial intelligence. I was a beta tester for OpenAI before they launched ChatGPT and have been studying data science ever since.<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://silas-raye.github.io/#projects" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://silas-raye.github.io/#projects" target="_blank">Check Out My Projects</a>
<br><br>I created a linear model capable of forecasting customer wait times for a small pizza business with a high degree of accuracy. I extracted twenty years of order data from a SQL database, cleaned the data in python and analyzed it R, and created visualizations, and built reports to help communicate my findings. The project was then implemented into the point of sale system and will increase efficiency by helping staff to predict wait times on takeout orders without disturbing the kitchen.<br><br>I achieved a return on investment of 20% over five years by buying the same stocks as wall street CEOs. I used a web scraper to collect data from the security and exchange commission's website (<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.sec.gov" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.sec.gov" target="_blank">sec.gov</a>). Next I used R to analyze and visualize the data. I discovered that insiders like CEOs and CFOs tend to beat the markets, sometimes by a lot, when they trade in company stock.<br><br>This was a project for my Statistical Learning class in which I attempted to forecast the prices of trading cards based on their in-game abilities. I utilized various forms of natural language processing, including bag of words, term frequency inverse document frequency, and large language models, as well as high-dimensional linear approaches like lasso and ridge regression. The program was able to predict the price of cards with some accuracy, but I am currently readjusting this project to improve and refine it, as it was one of my first serious data science projects.<br><br><br>I am an expert at querying and manipulating data in SQL. I also have a strong foundation in relational databases and database design.<br><br>I am proficient with Python and R. I am also versed in the relevant packages including NumPy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, and more. I also have some experience with C++, Java, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.<br><br>I pride myself on my ability to communicate insights to non-technical audiences using tools like Power BI and Tableau.<br><br>I am adept in all operating systems including Windows, Apple, and Linux. Additionally, I am proficient in a range of software tools. I am a quick learner, and I can swiftly adapt to new programs and technologies as needed.<br><br>
<br>

  <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://silas-raye.github.io/#" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://silas-raye.github.io/#" target="_blank">silas.raye@gmail.com</a>

<br>

  (352) 231-0747

<br>

  300 11th Ave North<br>
Nashville, TN 37203<br>
USA

<br>


<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Silas-Raye?tab=repositories" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Silas-Raye?tab=repositories" target="_blank"></a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.linkedin.com/in/silas-raye/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/silas-raye/" target="_blank"></a>


]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 03:03:18 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>